Guide to the Fred W. Voget Papers 1935-1996
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
- Photos, 1939-1989; Series VI; 2.5 linear feet
  - Tripod frame with buffalo head, Pryor, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] These sacred items will be put on the "center pole" of the sundance lodge. (Box-folder 20/43, Photo number 318(VI):014)
  - Tripod frame with buffalo head, Pryor, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 20/44, Photo number 318(VI):015)
  - "Baby cave" at Pryor, Montana, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Baby Cave (Baakaatitshiwishe or baby footprints.) Pryor, Montana. This place is located right behind where the Baptist Church is today. (Box-folder 21/1, Photo number 318(VI):016)
  - Henry Big Day with daughter, Pryor, Montana, 1939; [From Aaron Brien] The bundle in the background can be hanging outside for a number of reasons that only the owner may know. (Box-folder 21/2, Photo number 318(VI):017)
  - Medicine bundle belonging to Henry Big Day's father-in-law hung on west side of house, Pryor, Montana, undated (Box-folder 21/3, Photo number 318(VI):018)
  - Picnic in the Big Horn Mountains, WY, July 4, 1940 (Box-folder 21/4, Photo number 318(VI):019)
  - Portion of the Medicine Wheel, Big Horn Mountains, Wyoming, July 4, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] A portion of Bighorn medicine wheel. (Box-folder 21/5, Photo number 318(VI):020)
  - Main business section of Pryor, Montana, 1939; [From Aaron Brien] The Apsaalooke refer to Pryor, Montana, as "Baahpuua" (They Shoot the Rock). This area has many names, this is most common. (Box-folder 21/6, Photo number 318(VI):021)
  - Main business section of Pryor, Montana, 1939 (Box-folder 21/7, Photo number 318(VI):022)
  - Wolf Mountains near Lodge Grass, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] The Apsaalooke refer to the Wolf Mountains as "Cheetish" (Wolf's Teeth) or "Aluuwiluttuua" (Where They Get Red Clay). (Box-folder 21/8, Photo number 318(VI):023)
  - Medicine Wheel, Big Horn Mountains, Wyoming, July 4, 1940 (Box-folder 21/9, Photo number 318(VI):024)
  - Medicine Wheel, Big Horn Mountains, Wyoming, July 4, 1940 (Box-folder 21/10, Photo number 318(VI):025)
  - Medicine Wheel, Big Horn Mountains, Wyoming, July 4, 1940 (Box-folder 21/11, Photo number 318(VI):026)
  - Unidentified building, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] Round Hall in Crow Agency Montana. Apsaalooke call this building "Awaasuuchichiaxa" (Round House). It was built in the 1930's. It was torn down around 2006. (Box-folder 21/12, Photo number 318(VI):027)
  - Cemetery, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Cemetery at the Little Bighorn Battle Site. This is not a cemetery but rather the markers of where bodies were found. (Box-folder 21/13, Photo number 318(VI):028)
  - Scenic view, undated (Box-folder 21/14, Photo number 318(VI):029)
  - Woman holding baby at Crow Fair, 1940 (Box-folder 21/15, Photo number 318(VI):030)
  - Man holding baby at Crow Fair, 1940 (Box-folder 21/16, Photo number 318(VI):031)
  - Crow camp scene, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] this picture was taken at the Annual Crow Fair. (Box-folder 21/17, Photo number 318(VI):032)
  - Chief Holds-the-Enemy wearing Hudson Bay coat, 1939; [From Aaron Brien] Holds-the-Enemy wearing Hudson Bay coat. Holds the enemy was not a Chief but he was a respected elder among the Apsaalooke. His father, Pretty Eagle, was a Chief. (Box-folder 21/18, Photo number 318(VI):033)
  - Chief Holds-the-Enemy, Prior, Montana, 1939; [From Aaron Brien] Holds-the-Enemy was not a Chief but he was a respected elder among the Apsaalooke. His father, Pretty Eagle, was a Chief. (Box-folder 21/19, Photo number 318(VI):034)
  - Camp views of annual Crow Fair, 1939 (Box-folder 21/20, Photo number 318(VI):035)
  - Camp views of annual Crow Fair, 1939 (Box-folder 21/21, Photo number 318(VI):036)
  - Folka Lefthand combing her hair, Crow Fair, 1939 (Box-folder 21/22, Photo number 318(VI):037)
  - Camp view at annual Crow Fair, 1939 (Box-folder 21/23, Photo number 318(VI):038)
  - Women with children, Crow Fair, 1940 (Box-folder 21/24, Photo number 318(VI):039)
  - Women with children, Crow Fair, 1940 (Box-folder 21/25, Photo number 318(VI):040)
  - Eating at the annual Crow Fair, 1939 (Box-folder 21/26, Photo number 318(VI):041)
  - Eating at the annual Crow Fair, 1939 (Box-folder 21/27, Photo number 318(VI):042)
  - Ruth Backbone and Elaine Mikalson at Crow Fair, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] Ruth Backbone would later be known as "Ruth Alden." (Box-folder 21/28, Photo number 318(VI):043)
  - Two men observing fair, 1940 (Box-folder 21/29, Photo number 318(VI):044)
  - Two men and child on bench, 1940 (Box-folder 21/30, Photo number 318(VI):045)
  - Man in traditional dress, 1940 (Box-folder 21/31, Photo number 318(VI):046)
  - Pete Lefthand at Crow Fair, 1939 (Box-folder 21/32, Photo number 318(VI):047)
  - Camp scene, undated (Box-folder 21/33, Photo number 318(VI):048)
  - Camp scene, undated (Box-folder 21/34, Photo number 318(VI):049)
  - Unidentified family eating, undated (Box-folder 21/35, Photo number 318(VI):050)
  - Man and children in camp area at Crow Fair, 1939; [From Aaron Brien] Pete Left Hand and child at camp during Crow Fair. (Box-folder 21/36, Photo number 318(VI):051)
  - Teepee, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] Little Nest's Painted Teepee. This Teepee most likely belonged to Little Nest. He was known for the feather figures on the outside of his teepee opposite of the door. He received this from a vision during a fasting some years before. These feathers are known as "Feather Flag." (Box-folder 21/37, Photo number 318(VI):052)
  - Three men on horseback facing camera, circa 1940 (Box-folder 21/38, Photo number 318(VI):053)
  - Henry Big Day and horse at Crow Fair, undated (Box-folder 21/39, Photo number 318(VI):054)
  - Henry Big Day and horse at Crow Fair, undated (Box-folder 21/40, Photo number 318(VI):055)
  - Henry Big Day and horse at Crow Fair, undated (Box-folder 21/41, Photo number 318(VI):056)
  - Henry Big Day and horse at Crow Fair, undated (Box-folder 21/42, Photo number 318(VI):057)
  - Henry Big Day at Crow Fair, undated (Box-folder 21/43, Photo number 318(VI):058)
  - Henry Big Day and unknown man on horseback at Crow Fair, undated (Box-folder 21/44, Photo number 318(VI):059)
  - Horse with fancy bridle and breast plate for Crow Fair parade, 1940 (Box-folder 21/45, Photo number 318(VI):060)
  - Assembling for the Crow Fair parade in Northeast section of camp, Crow Agency, Montana, 1939; [From Aaron Brien] Northeast section of the camp. (Box-folder 21/46, Photo number 318(VI):061)
  - Assembling for the Crow Fair parade, 1939; [From Aaron Brien] Northeast section of the camp. Closer view. (Box-folder 21/47, Photo number 318(VI):062)
  - Crow Fair parade, August 1940; [From Aaron Brien] Robert Yellowtail. (Box-folder 21/48, Photo number 318(VI):063)
  - Crow Fair parade, 1940 (Box-folder 21/49, Photo number 318(VI):064)
  - Gathering for costume judging at Crow Fair, 1939 (Box-folder 21/50, Photo number 318(VI):065)
  - Line of men on horseback in traditional clothing, undated (Box-folder 21/51, Photo number 318(VI):066)
  - Crow Fair parade, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Robert Yellowtail. (Box-folder 21/52, Photo number 318(VI):067)
  - Crow Fair parade, undated (Box-folder 21/53, Photo number 318(VI):068)
  - Crow Fair parade passing on, 1939 (Box-folder 21/54, Photo number 318(VI):069)
  - Crow Fair parade passing on, 1939 (Box-folder 21/55, Photo number 318(VI):070)
  - Two men on horseback with American flag, teepees in background, undated (Box-folder 21/56, Photo number 318(VI):071)
  - Men on horseback carrying flag, undated (Box-folder 21/57, Photo number 318(VI):072)
  - Crow Fair, Crow Agency, Montana, 1939 (Box-folder 21/58, Photo number 318(VI):073)
  - Parade at Crow Fair, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] Robert Yellowtail. (Box-folder 21/59, Photo number 318(VI):074)
  - Raising teepee at Crow Fair, 1940 (Box-folder 21/60, Photo number 318(VI):075)
  - Henry Big Day at Crow Fair, undated (Box-folder 21/61, Photo number 318(VI):076)
  - Herb Reed at Crow Fair, 1940 (Box-folder 21/62, Photo number 318(VI):077)
  - Reed kids and Thelma in camp at Crow Fair, 1940 (Box-folder 21/63, Photo number 318(VI):078)
  - Three children at Crow Fair, circa 1940 (Box-folder 21/64, Photo number 318(VI):079)
  - Small girl in traditional Crow dress, Crow Fair, circa 1940 (Box-folder 21/65, Photo number 318(VI):080)
  - Suzy Yellowtail in bone elk tooth dress, undated (Box-folder 21/66, Photo number 318(VI):081)
  - Henry Big Day in traditional clothing with pinto horse, 1940 (Box-folder 21/67, Photo number 318(VI):082)
  - Henry Big Day on pinto, 1940 (Box-folder 21/68, Photo number 318(VI):083)
  - Camp scene with meat drying on pole at Crow Fair, Crow Agency, Montana, 1939 (Box-folder 21/69, Photo number 318(VI):084)
  - Camp scene with woman and child in foreground, undated (Box-folder 21/70, Photo number 318(VI):085)
  - Crow teepees with ramada-type shelter at Crow Fair, Crow Agency, Montana, 1939 (Box-folder 21/71, Photo number 318(VI):086)
  - Crow teepees with ramada-type shelter at Crow Fair, Crow Agency, Montana, 1939 (Box-folder 21/72, Photo number 318(VI):087)
  - Crow teepees, Crow Agency, Montana, 1940 (Box-folder 21/73, Photo number 318(VI):088)
  - Teepee, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Painted teepee. Possibly Little Nest's teepee. (Box-folder 21/74, Photo number 318(VI):089)
  - Teepee, undated (Box-folder 21/75, Photo number 318(VI):090)
  - Teepee, undated (Box-folder 21/76, Photo number 318(VI):091)
  - Crow teepees, undated (Box-folder 21/77, Photo number 318(VI):092)
  - Teepee and cars, Crow Fair, 1940 (Box-folder 21/78, Photo number 318(VI):093)
  - Child's play teepee, Crow, 1939 (Box-folder 21/79, Photo number 318(VI):094)
  - Old Cree madwoman, Yellow-woman (Mrs. Ball), Ball, and Joe Turns Back, Pryor, Montana, 1939 (Box-folder 21/80, Photo number 318(VI):095)
  - Crow women at Crow Fair, August 1939; [From Aaron Brien] Apsaalooke Women (Box-folder 21/81, Photo number 318(VI):096)
  - Women and children under canopy, Crow Fair, 1940 (Box-folder 21/82, Photo number 318(VI):097)
  - View of Crow Fair camp, 1940 (Box-folder 21/83, Photo number 318(VI):098)
  - View of Crow Fair camp, 1940 (Box-folder 21/84, Photo number 318(VI):099)
  - View of Crow Fair camp, 1940 (Box-folder 21/85, Photo number 318(VI):100)
  - View of Crow Fair camp, 1940 (Box-folder 21/86, Photo number 318(VI):101)
  - View of Crow Fair camp, 1940 (Box-folder 21/87, Photo number 318(VI):102)
  - View of Crow Fair camp, 1940 (Box-folder 21/88, Photo number 318(VI):103)
  - View of Crow Fair camp, 1940 (Box-folder 21/89, Photo number 318(VI):104)
  - Returning war party at Crow Fair, 1939; [From Aaron Brien] It is the Apsaalooke belief that, when a Clan Father makes a "good wish" for the clan child it will come true. The praise song is one way of making that wish. (Box-folder 21/90, Photo number 318(VI):105)
  - Remnants of fort build by Cheyenne about five miles from Lodge Grass, Montana, undated (Box-folder 22/1, Photo number 318(VI):106)
  - War lodge, presumably left by Piegan, 1941 (Box-folder 22/2, Photo number 318(VI):107)
  - War lodge, presumably left by Piegan, 1941 (Box-folder 22/3, Photo number 318(VI):108)
  - Gathering, possibly for feast, undated (Box-folder 22/4, Photo number 318(VI):109)
  - Three boys at Crow Fair, 1939 (Box-folder 22/5, Photo number 318(VI):110)
  - Looking out over North Fork of Lodge Grass Creek, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/6, Photo number 318(VI):111)
  - Teepee Pole Springs in the Big Horn Mountains, 1941 (Box-folder 22/7, Photo number 318(VI):112)
  - Inspecting marriage gifts, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] It is Apsaalooke custom to give gifts to the newly married couple. An Apsaalooke mother will give a teepee and new dress as well as many household goods. This is a custom that is still practiced. (Box-folder 22/8, Photo number 318(VI):113)
  - Hartford Whitehip's marriage, inspecting gift of groom and bride's parents and kin, Lodge Grass, Montana, 1940 (Box-folder 22/9, Photo number 318(VI):114)
  - Whitehip marriage goods displayed, Lodge Grass, Montana, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] Gloria's Apsaalooke name was Weasel Song "Utteiishuhe." This was given to her by the well-respected Pryor Montana elder Plainfeather. (Box-folder 22/10, Photo number 318(VI):115)
  - Gloria Goes Ahead, Crow bride, with wedding gifts, Lodge Grass, Montana, 1950; [From Aaron Brien] Gloria was born in 1931 making her 9 years old in 1940. Gloria was married in 1950; [From Archives] The Gloria Goes Ahead photographs were dated by an earlier processor as 1940. (Box-folder 22/11, Photo number 318(VI):116)
  - Gloria Goes Ahead, Crow bride, inspecting wedding gifts, 1950 (Box-folder 22/12, Photo number 318(VI):117)
  - Crow bride and young groom (Gloria Goes Ahead and Barnard Cummins) with wedding presents, 1950; [From Aaron Brien] Bernard and Gloria Cummins looking at a "wedding gift horse." (Box-folder 22/13, Photo number 318(VI):118)
  - Possible wedding gift display, undated (Box-folder 22/14, Photo number 318(VI):119)
  - View of house, barn, and corrals, Pryor, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/15, Photo number 318(VI):120)
  - View of house, barn, and corrals, Pryor, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/16, Photo number 318(VI):121)
  - Tobacco garden, Lodge Grass, Montana, May 30, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Tobacco Garden fence. This Ceremony is called Oopawuussiio, "Putting tobacco in." To be involved in the Tobacco gardens one must be a member of the Tobacco Society "Baasshussuua." (Box-folder 22/17, Photo number 318(VI):122)
  - Tobacco garden 6 days after planting, Lodge Grass, Montana, May 30, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] View From inside the Tobacco Garden six days after planting. (Box-folder 22/18, Photo number 318(VI):123a)
  - Tobacco garden 6 days after planting, Lodge Grass, Montana, May 30, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] View From inside the Tobacco Garden six days after planting. (Box-folder 22/18, Photo number 318(VI):123b)
  - Woman cleaning hide with elkhorn adze, grandmother with child, 1940 (Box-folder 22/19, Photo number 318(VI):124)
  - Woman staking hide down, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] Unknown woman nailing hide down. (Box-folder 22/20, Photo number 318(VI):125)
  - Woman working on tanning hide, Lodge Grass, Montana, 1940 (Box-folder 22/21, Photo number 318(VI):126)
  - Woman tanning hide, Lodge Grass, Montana 1940 (Box-folder 22/22, Photo number 318(VI):127)
  - Hide stretched between pegs for tanning, 1939 (Box-folder 22/23, Photo number 318(VI):128)
  - Hide stretched between pegs for tanning, 1939 (Box-folder 22/24, Photo number 318(VI):129)
  - Woman-on-top-of-the-ground demonstrates fleshing of deer hide, 1941 (Box-folder 22/25, Photo number 318(VI):130)
  - Woman-on-top-of-the-ground softens hide by scraping, 1941 (Box-folder 22/26, Photo number 318(VI):131)
  - Two unidentified women, undated (Box-folder 22/27, Photo number 318(VI):132)
  - Two people, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Two unidentified people getting rest inside the Sundance lodge. (Box-folder 22/28, Photo number 318(VI):133)
  - Crow child in parade dress on black and white pinto, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] Unidentified Apsaalooke girl on black and white pinto parade horse. (Box-folder 22/29, Photo number 318(VI):134)
  - Crow child in parade dress on dark-colored horse, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] Unidentified Apsaalooke girl on sorrel parade horse. (Box-folder 22/30, Photo number 318(VI):135)
  - Crow feast after giveaway, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] It is common after any Apsaalooke "doings" to have a feed, as seen here. (Box-folder 22/31, Photo number 318(VI):136)
  - Dancing fraternity in background and circle of men playing hand games in foreground, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] Apsaalooke Hot Dancers and singers, with children watching in foreground. The Voget description states these men are dancing and a group of men are playing handgames. It was mistaken. Singers were taken for handgame players. (Box-folder 22/32, Photo number 318(VI):137)
  - Eddie Roundface signaling in Handgame, Pryor, circa 1939-1940; [From Aaron Brien] This a game played only in the winter. It is a Apsaalooke taboo to play this game during the summer months. (Box-folder 22/33, Photo number 318(VI):138)
  - Yellow Face and Holds-the-Enemy at Crow Fair, August 1939; [From Aaron Brien] Yellow Face in this image may be "Half Yellow Face" who was best known for his role as a scout for the 7th Calvary. But he himself was what the Apsaalooke refer to as "Pipe Carrier" commonly known as a war leader. Holds-the-Enemy was the son of respected Chief Pretty Eagle. (Box-folder 22/34, Photo number 318(VI):139)
  - Holds-the-Enemy on horseback at crow Fair, 1939 (Box-folder 22/35, Photo number 318(VI):140)
  - Branding on Reed farm, Arliss Whiteman, undated (Box-folder 22/36, Photo number 318(VI):141)
  - Branding by Yellowtail, the Crow Superintendent, undated (Box-folder 22/37, Photo number 318(VI):142)
  - Branding, undated (Box-folder 22/38, Photo number 318(VI):143)
  - Gathering poles for sun dance lodge, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Two unidentified men near unused sweat lodge, Crow Reservation This description says "Gathering poles for sundance lodge. But in folder 7 of box 22 this same picture states "Teepee Pole Springs in the Big Horn Mountains." It is important to note that Tipi Pole Springs and Crow Agency are not close to each other. (Box-folder 22/39, Photo number 318(VI):144)
  - Gathering poles for sun dance lodge, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Getting ready to construct the Sundance lodge, Crow Agency. From looking at the negative this is not gathering poles for the sundance but it is sundance related. This is known as "aweeleennissuua" or "Bitaalasshia paaxaau". This is a ceremony done right before the Sundance. (Box-folder 22/40, Photo number 318(VI):145)
  - Gathering poles for sun dance lodge, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Getting ready to construct the Sundance lodge. This picture looks like the same event as folder 40. (Box-folder 22/41, Photo number 318(VI):146)
  - Gathering poles for sun dance lodge, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Unidentified men talking, the "center pole" lying on the ground, Crow Agency. This picture looks like the same event as folder 40. (Box-folder 22/42, Photo number 318(VI):147)
  - Gathering poles for sun dance lodge, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Apsaalooke men getting ready to raise the Center Pole, Crow Agency. This picture is of the "Raising of the center pole". (Box-folder 22/43, Photo number 318(VI):148)
  - Gathering poles for sun dance lodge, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Construction of the Sundance Lodge, Crow Agency. This was only the second sundance among the Apsaalooke since 1875. The first being in Pryor, Montana, one month before. (Box-folder 22/44, Photo number 318(VI):149)
  - Charlie Ten/bear talks with signs while Truhujo listens, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/45, Photo number 318(VI):150)
  - Loading poles for sun dance lodge, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Loading the "Center Pole" Crow Agency, Montana. The sponger for this sundance was Gus Other Medicine and the Sundance Chief was John Truhujo. (Box-folder 22/46, Photo number 318(VI):151)
  - Truck dragging wagon with poles, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/47, Photo number 318(VI):152)
  - Slender pole draped with material, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/48, Photo number 318(VI):153)
  - Tripod in foreground, seated people in background, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/49, Photo number 318(VI):154)
  - Woodpile which lay south of the buffalo head, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/50, Photo number 318(VI):155)
  - Preparing center pole, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Unknown men preparing the center pole to be raised, Crow Agency, Montana. (Box-folder 22/51, Photo number 318(VI):156)
  - Preparation of sun dance lodge center pole, Charlie Ten/bear in immediate foreground, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/52, Photo number 318(VI):157)
  - Charlie Ten/bear gesturing, Truhujo visible, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/53, Photo number 318(VI):158)
  - Messenger eagle marking center pole location, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Stuffed eagle that is going to be placed on the Center pole, Crow Agency. The Apsaalooke say that the eagle is placed on the Center pole to represent freedom. The eagle has no boundaries. As well as the Apsaalooke belief that all birds carry our prayers to the Creator. (Box-folder 22/54, Photo number 318(VI):159)
  - Messenger eagle resting on cottonwood foliage frame pointed to sun, marking location of center pole, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/55, Photo number 318(VI):160)
  - Messenger eagle, undated (Box-folder 22/56, Photo number 318(VI):161)
  - Ready to attach buffalo head to center pole, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/57, Photo number 318(VI):162)
  - Attaching buffalo head to center pole, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] The Center pole has three main objects attached to it. The Buffalo head, Eagle and a Bundle of willows. The Center pole also has three or four black lines at the base marking the length of the dance. (Box-folder 22/58, Photo number 318(VI):163)
  - Raising center pole at Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/59, Photo number 318(VI):164)
  - Raising the center pole, undated (Box-folder 22/60, Photo number 318(VI):165)
  - Raising center pole for sun dance, 1940 (Box-folder 22/61, Photo number 318(VI):166)
  - Raising center pole for sun dance, 1941 (Box-folder 22/62, Photo number 318(VI):167)
  - Raising center pole for sun dance, 1940 (Box-folder 22/63, Photo number 318(VI):168)
  - Stabilizing center pole for sun dance, 1941 (Box-folder 22/64, Photo number 318(VI):169)
  - Stages in lodge construction for Crow sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/65, Photo number 318(VI):170)
  - Stages in lodge construction for Crow sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/66, Photo number 318(VI):171)
  - Constructing sun dance lodge, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/67, Photo number 318(VI):172)
  - Center pole with buffalo head, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/68, Photo number 318(VI):173)
  - Center pole with buffalo head, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/69, Photo number 318(VI):174)
  - Center pole with buffalo head, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 22/70, Photo number 318(VI):175)
  - Men waiting in and by truck, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Apsaalooke Hot Dancers in back of pickup truck. It looks like these dancers are getting ready to take part in the Crow Fair Parade. (Box-folder 22/71, Photo number 318(VI):176)
  - Early sun dance lodge construction, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] At this point the sundance lodge is almost up. They are putting up the rafter poles of which there are 12, to represent the 12 new moons of the year. (Box-folder 22/72, Photo number 318(VI):177)
  - Structure of sun dance lodge, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/1, Photo number 318(VI):178)
  - Distant view of empty sun dance lodge, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Distant view of the Sundance lodge shortly after the dance is over. (Box-folder 23/2, Photo number 318(VI):179)
  - Distant view of occupied sun dance lodge, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] This picture looks like it was taken on the "painting day" which is the most important day of the dance. (Box-folder 23/3, Photo number 318(VI):180)
  - Very distant view of sun dance lodge, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/4, Photo number 318(VI):181)